# Nicholas Howard

nickhoward.dev ♦nhowar@uwo.ca ♦ (581) 922-3342 ♦ London, ON

# **Objective**

Creative and diligent computer science student with well developed technical proficiency that builds upon six years of managerial experience in the reclamation industry. I am eager to apply my technical skills and well as teamwork and problem solving abilities to projects in software development.

## Education

University of Western Ontario 2021-present Honors Specialization in Computer Science. London, Ontario

- Dean's Honor List 2021, 2022, & 2023
- Maintained an average of 88%

### **Technical Skills**

- Object Oriented Programming in Python, Java, and C with particular proficiency in
- MySQL & Database Management
- Linux Bash and package management
- HTML & CSS
- GitHub and Version Control
- Jira, Confluence

## **Projects**

- **LogicLand** An educational app that teaches formal logic and foundational computer science concepts through the use of logic gates. Completed as a group project for Western in which I was responsible for the user interface and collaborated with another member on the logic circuits. Programmed in Java using JavaFX.
  - A demonstration can be found here <a href="https://www.voutube.com/watch?v=51Ki6Te4YFs">https://www.voutube.com/watch?v=51Ki6Te4YFs</a>
  - The code can be found here https://github.com/readvgroup1/LogicLand

### Soft Skills

#### Leadership

As a Manager at Little Smokey, I was responsible for hiring, training and daily management of a crew of up to eleven planters in the reforestation of previously logged land in Northern Alberta. Each summer my crew and I would plant approximately a million trees and reclaim over 700 hectares of land.

## Analytical Thinking and Logistics

At Little Smokey, I planned and executed daily deliveries of tens of thousands of seedlings by various means such as ATV and via helicopter. I would analyze the map to ensure that the correct tree species was planted into the correct type of land for each of my planters.

## Work Experience

- Little Smokey Forestry Services Foreman Grande Prairie, AB May 2017 August 2022 Whistler Blackcomb September 2016 May 2017 Logistics associate Whistler, BC
- Gentech Roofing August 2015 September 2016 Labourer Mississauga, ON
- Summit Screen Printing Supplies October 2013— August 2015 Penticton, BC Assisted in the purchase, relocation, and modernization of a distribution business.